Anthony Reid

37 Nelson Drive Cannock WS12 2GF Tel: 07801700346

Email: antreid91@gmail.com

Technical Skills:

Experience designing and implementing DevOps methodologies such as Configuration Management (Puppet & Ansible), CI/CD (Jenkins), Infrastructure as Code (Vagrant & Terraform), building custom tools where needed and Implementing automated test suites.

Experience working with Cisco Routing, Switching and Firewalls.

Advanced Linux System Administration & Windows System Administration

Scripting in multiple languages

Designing, Implementing, Securing and Managing Virtualised and Cloud Based infrastructure (AWS).

Experience providing 3rd line support and experience being the highest escalation point in event of a system outage.

Experience of building monitoring suites from the ground up including the automation of monitoring with a variety of tools (Icinga, Graphite, Grafana, InfluxDB, StatsD, CollectD, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Logstash, Zabbix, Manage Engine)

Extensive knowledge of Source Control and Source Control processes using SVN, Mercurial and Github.

Experience evaluating, testing and implementing OpenSource technologies.

IP Networking & Security (Previously CCNA certified)

Relevant Employment

May 2013 - Present Cognito IQ, DevOps Engineer / Site Reliability Engineer

The main duties of my role include:

- Working towards an automated, scalable and reliable platform whilst streamlining the development - production pipeline
- Architecting, implementing and securing the cloud infrastructure in AWS whilst optimising performance where possible
- Subject Matter Expert for Configuration Management using Puppet and Ansible
- Subject Matter Expert for the Platform (MySQL, RabbitMQ, Apache, Tomcat)
- Building an immutable system to save on development costs
- Continuously Improving the platform through testing, tuning and upgrading components
- Building, Automating and Maintaining a custom monitoring system for a range of different solutions

- Providing in and out of hours support as a final point of escalation for third line engineers
- Providing training and assistance to new members of the DevOps team and new members of the company on the development and deployment process.
- Automating system administration of the Cognito platform where possible

July 2011 - September 2012 Cognito IQ, Network Support Engineer (IP)

As part of the Cognito Network Support team we were responsible monitoring of the network as part of a 24x7 rota and ensuring customer service is available at all times. We had strict SLA's to meet in the event of an issue however also took on project work. As part of this role I was able to take part in the Frame Replacement Project which meant moving 90 customers from frame relay connections onto IPSec VPNs or BT Wholesale Ethernet connections.

Responsibilities

- Handling day to day issues with the Cognito network. Ranging from problems with the Cognito applications to issues with customer links.
- Implementing customer links
- Completing daily and weekly checks
- Linux System Administration
- Providing in and out of hours 2nd line support

Education

2009 - 2013

University of Derby - BSc (Hons) Computer Networks 2:2

From the course I have been able to consider my understanding of computer networks to a much greater level from that which I studied at sixth form. I am developing a practical nature in the creation and maintenance of network systems. I am also furthering my knowledge in Wireless Networks. During each network based module of the course we attend a practical exam in which we create a network based on what we have learnt, and implement in a real environment.

Modules Include: Computer Network Concepts, Network Communications and Routing, Network Interfaces, Wireless Networks, Systems Analysis, Information Systems Management, Information security principles, Multi-User databases, Computer Architecture, Network Security and Wide Area Networks.

Interests:

Sport

I was a member of the Derby Braves American Football team as a running back whilst I was at university, prior to this I also frequently practiced a range of combat sports. I enjoy going to the gym 3-5 times a week.

References available upon request.